Oguadalajara, Jalisco, Mexico 🕓 3322355423 Ogualajara, Jalisco, Mexico Ogualajara, Jalisco, Ogualajara, Oguala

Profiles in <u>hector-gomez-gdl</u>

Summary

IT Engineer 1 year of experience. I have led projects that significantly improved performance and efficiency in companies such as Robert Bosch. My focus includes process optimization. Passionate about continuous learning, with Linux and bash and Python scripting knowledge, AWS, git, agile methodologies.

Experience

Aceros Murillo

July 2024 - Present

Software Analyst

Guadalajara, Jalisco, Mexico

- I provided technical support to computer equipment and software, solving incidents and optimizing hardware performance.
- I installed and configured security cameras and structured cabling.
- I administered networks with firewalls, ensuring the security and connectivity of the infrastructure.
- •I implemented and managed servers and cloud solutions based on Synology.
- I administered enterprise software for ticket management, accounting modules, human resources

Robert Bosch Mexico

July 2023 - June 2024

Intern IT Support

Guadalajara, Jalisco, Mexico

- I managed the inventory of technology equipment, including computers, cell phones, and printers, performing monthly reviews to ensure availability and optimal functioning of resources.
- I streamlined inventory management processes using Excel and Python, which improved accuracy and reduced administration time.
- by implementing improvements in incident tracking and resolution. • I performed preventive and corrective maintenance of computer equipment, networks,

• I managed ticketing software, reducing the backlog of tickets from 300 to 30 in 11 months

routers and switches and managed warranties, ensuring equipment was always operational. Provided induction to new employees on the use of systems and equipment, improving

Education

Universidad de Guaddalajara

January 2020 - January 2024

bachelor's degree

Computer Science

9.2 GPA

Honors: Honors in the subject of Web Programming and Databases.

Volunteering

CUCEI- Social Service

January 2023- August 2024

Technical support and project management

their integration and productivity from day one.

Guadalajara, Jalisco Mexico

- Lab Technical Support: I provided technical support resolving hardware and software issues, covering printers, routers, computers, laptops, 3D printers and cameras. I implemented efficient solutions that improved team productivity.
- Requirements Management and Event Support: I documented and gathered client requirements during an IEEE event, managing the team and optimizing resources using WordPress to meet project objectives efficiently.
- Customer Service Process Optimization: I implemented process improvements in the customer service department, resulting in reduced response time and improved customer ratings.

Courses

Amazon Web Services

AWS Re/Star Program Student

Activities and societies: - I participated in an intensive AWS re/Start bootcamp where I acquired skills in:

- SQL and Python for DB management and scripting.
- AWS services such as S3, Lambda, EC2, VPC, and Security Groups.
- Cloud fundamentals and security best practices.
- Scripting and automation development with Python and Shell.
- Configuration and monitoring of cloud infrastructures.
- Collaboration on group projects and technical troubleshooting. Activities and societies: I participated in an intensive AWS re/Start bootcamp where I acquired skills in: - SQL and Python for DB management and scripting. - AWS services such as S3, Lambda, EC2, VPC, and Security Groups. - Cloud fundamentals and security best practices. - Scripting and automation development with Python and Shell. - Configuration and monitoring of cloud infrastructures. - Collaboration on group projects and technical troubleshooting....see more

Skills	Team Player	Proactive	Flexibility	responsibility	adaptability
	••••	••••	• • • •	••••	• • • •
	Python	AWS	Scrum		
	• • • • 0	• • • • •	• • • •		

Certifications

Application development in the Azure cloud **GRUPO EDUIT**

November 2024

 $\textbf{Skills:} \ \textbf{Cloud Computing} \cdot \textbf{Cloud Applications} \cdot \textbf{Fundamentals azure} \cdot \textbf{Microsoft Azure}$

Languages

English B2

Certification Euromen International